Fabian Shallari

Birthdate: May 4th, 1992

E-mail: hi@fabio.codes
Website: http://fabio.codes

Github: https://github.com/FabianShallari

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/fabianshallari

Skype: fabio.shallari Phone: +355696149313

Address: Rruga Don Bosko, Pallati TID, Tirana, Albania

FREELANCE PROJECTS

Charlie

Android Developer

Charlie is a musical companion. It lets you recognize songs and makes musical suggestions in a UX-friendly chat interface:

- Built and deployed Android app from scratch.
- Helped with the design by providing feedback during the design sprints based on personal experience with Material Design and Android UI and UX implementation.
- Integrated with Discogs and Gracenote and YouTube APIs.
- Play Store Link: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=guru.charlie.android

WeTick

Android Developer

WeTick is a social network that allows its users to challenge each other

- Build and Deployed Android app from scratch and integrated with the backend
- Successfully converted the iOS design to a Material Design language
- Play Store Link: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.wetick.android

Ecovolis

Android Developer

Helped the environment-friendly local non-profit organization Ecovolis launch their Android app in the Play Store. Users can find the nearest Bike Repair Shop, roads which have bike lanes and take pictures to report occupied bike lanes.

• Play Store Link: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.ecovolis.android

Ilko Travel

Full Stack Web Developer

Worked as full-time contractor for an AngularJS client with a Rails & PostgreSQL backend web app. Developed in-house web app that manages buses, clients, trips and tickets of an international travelling company. It was successfully deployed to Heroku.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Pomodoro sh.p.k October 2015 — October 2016

Android Developer

Pomodoro Pizza & More is a new Albanian startup that specializes in food delivery built Android app from scratch and integrated with the backend services. Adapted the iOS design of the iOS app to a Material Design Language, in order to make the app familiar with the platform users, enhancing UX and familiarity

• Play Store Link: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=al.pomodoro.android

Scopic Software June 2015 — October 2015

Android Developer

I worked as an in-house Android developer for the American - based Scopic Software. Collaborated directly with clients in developing, optimising and updating their apps. Most of the work included new features implementation and bugs fixing.

- Driver's Companion Internal app
- Scourby YouBible Client app. Bugs fixing and features

Institute of Forensic Medicine October 2013 - November 2014

IT Support

Worked part-time as IT Support during my University years. Helped fix common hardware issues for the institute's PCs and printers.

EDUCATION

Bachelor in Computer Engineering, October 2016

Polytechnic University of Tirana

Some of my favorite courses:

- Computer Networks Andrew Tanenbaum Book
- Operating Systems Andrew Tanenbaum Book
- Algorithms and Data Structures Implemented a QuadTree data structure in C which
 parsed a 1/0 (black/white) image representation and stored it in nodes and also did
 the reverse of restoring it from the tree-structure to the image representation.

SKILLS

All these skills were gained in the last 2 years from working various projects in Android and Web Development:

- Android Development
- Model-View-Presenter (MVP) Architecture in Android
- Reactive and Functional Programming with RxJava
- Google Play Services Integration. Location, Maps, Cloud Messages
- Material Design Implementation
- JavaScript
- HTML/CSS
- Ruby/Rails

INTERESTS

- Kotlin
- JavaScript Front-End Frameworks (React and Angular2)
- JavaScript Backend, Node.js
- Vert.x
- Loopback.io
- Backend Scalability
- Docker Containers
- Google Cloud Platform APIs